History of the Written Word: Pages from the Past, 2400 BCE-1920 CE Z4 .H58
Lilly Library
- Leaf (engraving, entitled, "Di Carlo D'Angio") from La Sicilia di Filippo Paruta, a compilation of Sicilian medals by Paruta, Secretary to the Palermitan Senate in the first half of the 17th Century, and Leonardo Agostini, Supervisor of Antiquities to the Pope. Published by Marco Maier at Lyons, 1697; 37 x 24 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (p. 5) from Anacreon, Bion and Moschus, a book of poetry in the manner of the Greek poet, Anacreon, and bearing the imprint: I.B. Bodonius, Regis Catholici Typographus Parma, 1791; 15 x 10 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (p. 191) from The Complete Measurer, by Wm. Hawney (Philomath); printed at Dublin by R. Jackson, 1785; 17 x 10 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (p. 57) from Murray's English Grammar, by Lindley Murray, printed at Boston by Robert Davies & Co., 1856; 16 x 10 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (engraving, "Tab. CCCLVI," I.G. Pintz, sculps.) from Scheuchzer Bible engraving, an example of copper engraving from the well-known Bible, 1731; 43 x 26 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (B5, p. 15**) from Medalische Historie der Republyk Van Holland, a volume of copper engravings. Pierre Bizot was the author of this book. This leaf is from the 2nd edition printed in Amsterdam, 1690; 23 x 18 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (B2, p. 18) from an Increase Mather sermon, an American incunable leaf. This comes from the hand of the brother Cotton Mather, although there was a sister named Increase, 1665; 15 x 9 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (p. 489) from a French missal, from the press of J. Claye, Paris. This leaf is notable because the decorative borders are woodcut reproductions of a Fifteenth Century Book of Hours, 1858; 17 x12 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (p. 159) from Child Christopher and Goldilind the Fair, written by William Morris, in his famous Chaucer type, and printed by him in a limited edition at his Kelmscott Press, 1895; 15 x 11 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (plate 247, entitled, "White-breasted Nuthatch") from an Audubon lithograph, printed at New York. The second edition of the most famous set of bird prints in the world. This leaf is from The Quadrapeds and is an original engraving, as Audubon was both the artist and the engraver on stone, 1856; 27 x 17 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (plate V, by G.T. Sanford) from Natural History Lithography, by Ebenezer Emmons, M.D., published by the State of New York and printed by Charles Van Benthuysen of Albany, New York, 1851; 29 x 22 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (p. 291) from a Greek miniature, printed at Oxford by N. Bliss. This leaf is a fine example of Greek type, set to the classic Iliad, 1810; 12 x 7 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (p. 65, "Novelties for July") from Goudy's Ladies Book, printed at Philadelphia, 1860; 23 x 15 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (copper engraving) from Spieghel der Schriftkonste, a book of calligraphy, by Jan van den Velde, printed in Rotterdam, 1605; 22 x 33 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf from a Persian manuscript, viz., the poem Sháhnáma of Firdausi, early 17th century; 33 x 21 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (p. 71) from The Luck of the Roaring Camp, by Bret Harte. The 1st illustrated edition of Harte's works, published by James R. Osgood & Co., Boston, Mass., 1872; 36 x 28 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (p. 51, steel engraving vignette) from Gallery of English and American Poets. Printed in Philadelphia by C. Sherman & Son, and published by E.H. Butler & Co, 1859; 28 x 19 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (p. 203) from Coustumes de Touraine, a digest of laws in force in that Duchy. Printed by Estienne La Tour in the City of Tour, 1661; 24 x 18 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (C2, p. 27) from De Indiae Utriusque, Re Naturali et Medica, an illustrated work on the natural history of "Both Indies," by William Piso, printed by the Elzevirs at their Amsterdam press, 1658; 37 x 23 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (V, p. 134, with engraving) from Symbola Politica; printed by Elsiver in Amsterdam, around mid-century; 13 x 7 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf from a Callot etching, an original and fine impression (a rendering on copperplate by intaglio) by Jacques Callot. From his second or Lorraine period, 1621-1631; 7 x 10 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (engraving "Marci XI") from a German Bible miniature, printed in Frankfurt am Main as found in the Martin Luther translation printed by Balthasar Christoph Wustens. These perfect one inch miniatures are a rarity, 1664; 40 x 64 mm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf from Virorum Illustrium &c., a collection of portraits of eminent monks and nuns of the Augustinian order many of whom suffered martyrdom in far distant lands. This book was printed by George Czernoch at Prague; the copper engravings are by Johann Damperviel and G. de Groos, 1674; 30 x 18 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf (P1) from Ethico Politicorum, a book of emblems printed at Heidelberg by Clemens Ammon, 1666; 20 x 16 cm. (Volume 4)
- Leaf from the Collected Works of Geoffrey Chaucer, edited by Thomas Speght and printed in London. There were two issues of Chaucer bearing this date-the first printed by Adam Islip, the second by George Bishop. This leaf is from the Islip edition, 1598; 31 x 20 cm. (Volume 4)